After addressing missing data first,
بعد معالجة البيانات المفقودة أولاً،
cleaning for tidiness is usually the next logical step.
عادة ما تكون عملية تنظيف الترتيب هي الخطوة المنطقية التالية.
Since Hadley Wickham is the pioneer of tidy data,
وبما أن هادلي ويكهام هو رائد البيانات الدقيقة،
let's start this bit with a quote from his paper on the subject.
دعونا نبدأ هذا الشيء بقراءة من بحثه حول هذا الموضوع.
A huge amount of effort is spent cleaning data to get it ready for analysis,
يتم إهدار قدر كبير من الجهد على مسح البيانات لتصبح جاهزة للتحليل،
but there has been little research on how to make data
ولكن كان هناك القليل من الأبحاث حول كيفية جعل مسح البيانات
cleaning as easy and effective as possible.
سهلاً وفعالاً قدر الإمكان.
This paper tackles a small,
تتناول هذه الورقة مكونًا
but important, component of data cleaning: data tidying.
صغيرًا ولكنه مهمًا لمسح البيانات: ترتيب البيانات.
The key take away is that Tidy datasets are easy to manipulate.
يتمثل المفتاح الأساسي في سهولة التعامل مع مجموعات البيانات.
And in the context of data wrangling,
وفي سياق تعارض البيانات،
tidy datasets with data quality issues are almost always
من الأسهل دائمًا ترتيب مجموعات البيانات
easier to clean than non-tidy as they have data quality issues.
حسب مشكلات جودة البيانات لإجراء المسح بدلًا من غير المرتبة لأنها تحتوي على مشكلات في جودة البيانات.
That means, it's generally best to clean the tidiness issues first,
وهذا يعني، أنه من الأفضل بشكل عام مسح مشكلات الترتيب أولًا،
which are our structural issues,
وهي مشكلاتنا الهيكلية،
then clean the quality issues,
ثم مسح مشكلات الجودة،
which are the content issues.
وهي مشكلات المحتوى.
For our example in this oral insulin clinical trial dataset,
بالنسبة لمثالنا في مجموعة بيانات التجربة الإكلينيكية للأنسولين عن طريق الفم،
we detected and documented four sections of the dataset that weren't tidy.
اكتشفنا وقمنا بتوثيق أربعة أقسام من مجموعة البيانات التي لم تكن مرتبة.
The first in the patients table,
الأول في جدول المرضى،
the two variables in one column,
والثاني في عمود واحد،
the contact column here,
عمود جهات الاتصال هنا،
phone number and email are in this one column.
رقم الهاتف والبريد الإلكتروني في هذا العمود.
Then in the treatment's table,
ثم في جدول العلاج،
there are three variables in two columns.
هناك ثلاثة متغيرات في عمودين.
Treatment and start dose and end dose in the auralin and novodra columns.
العلاج وجرعة البداية وجرعة النهاية في عمودي auralin وnovodra.
Start dose here, end dose here and
جرعة البداية، وجرعة النهاية هنا
the third treatment variable in the column headers auralin novodra.
ومتغير العلاج الثالث في رؤوس الأعمدة auralin novodra.
The third is that the adverse_reactions table shouldn't exist.
ويتمثل الثالث في ضرورة عدم وجود الجدول adverse_reactions.
And that the adverse reaction column should be part of the treatments table i.e.
وينبغي أن يكون عمود رد الفعل العكسي جزءًا من جدول العلاجات أي أن
this adverse_reaction column here should be joined with this treatments table here.
عمود adverse_reaction هنا يجب ضمه مع جدول العلاجات هنا.
And the fourth, is that the given_name and surname columns are duplicated in
والرابع، يتمثل في تكرار عمودي given_name واللقب في
the treatments in adverse_reactions table when it should only be in the patients table.
العلاجات في جدول adverse_reactions بينما ينبغي أن يوجد فقط في جدول المرضى.
And here the given_name and surname is displayed in the patients.info results.
وهنا يتم عرض given_name واللقب في نتائج patients.info.
Same goes for treatments.info and adverse_reactions.info.
يسري نفس الأمر على treatments.info وadverse_reactions.info.
So only a small set of tools are needed to deal with a wide range of untidy datasets.
لذلك هناك حاجة إلى مجموعة صغيرة فقط من الأدوات للتعامل مع مجموعة واسعة من مجموعات البيانات غير المرتبة.
You'll cover the most common ones in Pandas to fix these above four issues next.
سوف تغطي أكثرها شيوعا في Pandas لإصلاح هذه الأمور الأربعة المذكورة أعلاه بعد ذلك.